Pelham, Ruth; Papers apap408
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Ruth Pelham Papers
1978-2018
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap408
11.29 cubic ft.
This collection contains documents concerning the work of Ruth Pelham, a singer/songwriter and educator in the Albany, New York area who has been performing for decades in an effort to bring about peaceful communities through music. From the late 1970s to circa 2016, Pelham traveled in a mobile music program called the Music Mobile; singing, teaching, and writing songs with the community.
Content Description
This collection documents the ongoing work of the Albany, NY-based singer, songwriter, and educator Ruth Pelham.
The Arts in Education (AIE) Series includes files about Pelham's concerts, residences, workshops, and programs at various youth-centric and educational institutions. The Grant Funding series contains grant application packages, which includes financial and promotional materials as well as the grant application. The Albany Housing Authority series contains materials from several music and other creative arts projects that took place in the housing projects that comprise the Albany Housing Authority: Ida Yarbrough Homes, Ezra Prentice Homes, and Corning Homes.
Some files are restricted because they contain sensitive financial material or the personal information of individuals who were minors at the time of document creation.
Biographical Note
Born in 1949, Ruth Pelham grew up in Brooklyn, NY with ambitions to become a folksinger. When Pelham attended the University of Wisconsin in the Vietnam era, she became emboldened as a feminist and activist against injustice. Beginning in the 1970s, Pelham began touring Albany, NY neighborhoods with her Music Mobile, a mobile music program, as a friendship building initiative. This effort eventually expanded beyond Albany, even internationally, with Pelham touring cities in the Soviet Union and collaborating with Soviet artists. Pelham was also a consultant to the Havasupai tribe for 10 years and part of an effort to stop the construction of a uranium mine on their land.
Pelham's folk songs have been published in folk music journals and recorded by over 30 musicians, including Pete Seeger and Ronnie Gilbert, Holly Near, Guy Carawan, and more. In 1997, Pelham received an Arts Award from the Albany/Schenectady League of Arts and was inducted into the Capital Area Music Association's Hall of Fame the same year. Pelham has also received an award for her work on behalf of women by The National Organization for Women's Albany chapter. Pelham has been featured in multiple documentaries, co-authored books, and is a co-founder and member of the board of directors of the Children's Music Network.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted with the exception of a select number of files noted on the finding aid. Many of these files contain PII related to minors who attended Music Mobile events. For the purposes of fulfilling her grant obligations, Ruth Pelham needed to secure and retain this data and it contextualizes the administrative aspects of her work. Although the individuals in question are no longer minors, they were children at the time the events occurred, so the archivist elected to restrict this information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ruth Pelham donated all materials to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2022-2023.
Arrangement of the collection
The Ruth Pelham Papers are divided into 3 series: 1.) Arts in Education (AIE), 2.) Grant Funding, 3.) Albany Housing Authority (AHA). AIE is arranged alphabetically. Grant Funding and AHA are arranged chronologically. Any audio-visual materials that originally accompanied the documents in series 1 have been separated and rehoused.
Pelham, Ruth; Music Mobile; Folk music-United States; Music--Instruction and study; Grant proposals; Correspondence; Photographs; Albany, New York; Music; Art
- Arts in Education (AIE), 1988-2018; 1; 3.86 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  The Arts in Education Series documents Ruth Pelham's concerts, residences, workshops, and programs at various youth-centric and educational institutions. Included are song lyrics she distributed and/or developed with students in various stages of the writing process, legal and financial documentation, correspondence between Pelham and institutional staff (usually school faculty), photographs of events, personal notes, reflections on events, post-performance evaluations, and thank you notes from participants (usually youths). This series is a more intimate look at the inner processes that kept the Music Mobile's wheels turning beyond grant funding and fundraising.
  Researchers should note that Pelham often included promotional materials in her files that predate the dates of her residencies. For example, her residency at the Clark Street Developmental Learning School took place in 1995-1996, but contains promotional material from 1991 and is dated accordingly.
  - Academy of Holy Names, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academy of Holy Names, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albany Academy for Girls, Albany Academy for Boys, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Albany Hebrew Academy, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anna Devine Elementary School, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Athens Elementary School, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Averill Park School District - RESTRICTED, 2016-2017 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - Ballard Elementary School, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Beckman Elementary School, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ben Franklin Elementary School, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Benjamin Cosor Elementary School, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Berne-Knox-Westerlo Central School District, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bethlehem School District, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bradt Primary School, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Brinckerhoff Elementary School, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Broward County Before and After School Childcare Programs - RESTRICTED, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Broward County Schools Research, 2005-2008 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Brown School, 2002-2005 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bruclerhoff School, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Burnt Hills Middle School, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Cairo - Durham Elementary School, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cairo - Durham Elementary School, Worksheets, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Cambridge Central School, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Carroll Hill Elementary School, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Carroll Hill Elementary School, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Castleton Elementary School, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Castleton Elementary School, 2011-2013 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Chango Elementary School, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Chatham Elementary School, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Cherry Valley/Spring Field School, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cherry Valley/Spring Field School, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Children's School of Emma Willard, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Clark Street Developmental Learning School - RESTRICTED, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Corinth School, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - The Cornerstone School, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Cornwall Consolidated School, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Crosby Elementary School, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Delaware Avenue Senior Center in Albany, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Division Street School, 1996; 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Donald P. Sutherland School, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Duanesburg Afterschool Program, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Duanesburg Elementary School, 1997; 2005 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Dutchess Community College Performing Arts Showcase, 1996-1997; 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Edinburg Common School, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Edmeston Central School/Morning Program Reunion, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Forts Ferry School and North Colonie School, 1994-1995; 1997 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Gardner Dickenson Elementary School, 1993; 1997 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Genet School, 1988; 1990; 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Genet School, Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - George Washington Elementary School, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - George Washington Elementary School - RESTRICTED, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - George Washington Elementary School, 2000-2001; 2004 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Germantown Elementary School, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Germantown Elementary School, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Germantown Elementary School, CARE Smoke Free Celebration Day, 2004 (Cd 1)
  - Germantown Elementary School, CARE Smoke Free Celebration Day, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Gibraltar School, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Glebe Street School, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Glen-Worden Elementary School, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Glendahl School, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Grandview Elementary School - RESTRICTED, 1988; 1990-1991; 1993 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Greater Plains Elementary School, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Greenfield Center School, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Greenfield Center School, Songwriting, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Greenfield Elementary School, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Guilderland Central School (Guilderland Elementary and Pine Bush Elementary), 1994-1995; 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Guilderland High School, Young People's Concert, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Hamilton Elementary School, Correspondence - RESTRICTED, 1989; 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Hamilton Elementary School, DARE and Drug Prevention Project, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Handwritten Notes About Lincoln and Hamilton Schools, Undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Handwritten School Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Hillside Elementary School, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Hillside School, Undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Hoosic Valley Elementary, 1995; 1997; 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Hoosic Valley Elementary School, Preparation Tape Sent to School Prior to My Visit so Children Can Sing with Me During Concert, 2000 March 22 (Cassette 1)
  - Hoosic Valley Elementary School, Ruth Pelham Visit Prep Tape, Undated (Cassette 2)
  - Howe International Magnet School, 1999-2000; 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Hyde Park Elementary School, 2004; 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Irving Elementary School, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - John L. Edwards Elementary, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Kellogg Elementary School, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Kent Elementary School, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Kreiger School, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - La Grange Elementary School, 1998-1999; 2001 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Lake Avenue Elementary School, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Lake Avenue Elementary School, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lake Avenue Elementary School, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lake View Elementary School, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lanesboro School, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lincoln School, Correspondence, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Little Red Schoolhouse, 1995; 1998; 2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lynwood Elementary, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Margaretville Central School - RESTRICTED, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Martin Luther King Elementary School, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mater Christi School, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - McCarthy Funded Programming (St. Augustine, Sacred Heart School, St. Jude), 2011 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Mechanicville Elementary School, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Merritt Memorial School, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Milford Central School, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Milford Elementary School, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Milford School, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Miller Hill Elementary School, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Milton Elementary School/Middle Hope Elementary School, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Montessori School, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Morris Central School, 2000; 2002; 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - New Paltz Elementary School, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - North Warren Central School District, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Noxon Road Elementary School, 2004; 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Oak Grove Elementary School, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Ockawamick Elementary School, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Oneida School, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Our Lady of Victory, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Our Lady of Victory, "Living in My Neighborhood: Songs to Make a Positive Difference!", 2007 (Cd 2)
  - Overlook Primary School, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Paige Elementary School, Correspondence, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Palm Beach County School District Research, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Parochial Schools Programming Binder (1 of 3), 2000-2002; 2004; 2007 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Parochial Schools Programming Binder (2 of 3), 2000-2002; 2004; 2007 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Parochial Schools Programming Binder (3 of 3), 2000-2002; 2004; 2007 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Parochial Schools: Sacred Heart School, St. Jude's, St. Augustine's, 2011-2013; 2015 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Pleasant Valley Elementary School, 1994; 1999; 2002-2005 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Portsville Central School, 2004; 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Poestenkill Elementary School, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Poestenkill Elementary School, Peace Begins with You and Me, 2004 March 30 (Cd 3)
  - Project Headstart, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Queensburg Elementary School, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Ravena School, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Red Mill Elementary School, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Rice Square School, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Rider Elementary, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Roesseville Elementary School, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Rosendale School, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Rosendale School, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Ryan Road Elementary School, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Sacandaga Elementary School, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Sacred Heart School - RESTRICTED, 2009-2010; 2012 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Sacred Heart School, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Sacred Heart School, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Sacred Heart School Songwriting, Undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Sacred Heart School Songs, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Saddlewood Elementary School, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Saddlewood Elementary School, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Saddlewood Elementary School, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - The Sage Colleges, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Saxton's River Elementary, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Schenectady City Schools, 1989-1992; 1995; 1996 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - School #2, Undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Schuylerville Elementary School, 1997; 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Shalmont Elementary School, 1990; 1995 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Sherburne - Earville Elementary School, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Skano School and Tesago Elementary School, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Slingerlands Elementary School, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - St. Augustine School, 2009-2011 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - St. Augustine School, 2009-2012 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - St. Augustine School, 2009 June; 2010 February (Cd 4)
  - St. Augustine School, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - St. Augustine School at Our Lady of Hope, 2011 January 27 (Cd 5)
  - St. Clement's Regional Catholic School, 2009; 2011-2014 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - St. Clement's Regional Catholic School, "Room For Us All", 2002 (Cd 6)
  - St. Jude the Apostle School, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - St. Jude the Apostle School, 2007; 2009 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - St. Jude the Apostle School, 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - St. Jude the Apostle School, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - St. Jude the Apostle School, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - St. Jude the Apostle School, 5th and 6th Grade Evaluations, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - St. Jude the Apostle School, Student Work, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - St. Jude the Apostle School, Worksheets, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - St. Patrick's School, Music Mobile Day, 2001 February 8 (Floppy-disk 1)
  - Standford Central School, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Taconic Hills Central School, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Tamarack Elementary School, Undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Tecler Elementary School, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Ticonderoga Elementary School, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Traver Road Primary School, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Troy Catholic Schools (St. Augustine and St. Jude), 2007; 2009 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - (Troy) School #2, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - (Troy) School #2, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Troy School 14, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Troy School 14, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Troy School 14, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Troy School 14, International Night, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Troy School 16 and Troy School 18, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Troy School 18, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Turnpike Elementary School, 2004-2009 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Turnpike Elementary School, 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Turnpike Elementary School, Immigration/Naturalization Project (1 of 2), 1999-2004 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Turnpike Elementary School, Immigration/Naturalization Project (2 of 2), 1999-2004 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Vail Farm Elementary School, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Van Corlaer Elementary School, 1994-1995; 1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Various Research and Songwriting for Programs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Voorheesville Junior and Senior High School, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Wading River Elementary School, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Waterford School District and Museum, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Watervliet Elementary School, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - West Sand Lake Elementary School, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - West Sand Lake Elementary School, 2004-2006 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - West Sand Lake Elementary School, Student Work, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Wildwood School, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - William Barkley School, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Williams Elementary School, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Woodland Hills Montessori School, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Woodstock Elementary School, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Worcester Community Schools, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Work Funded by McCarthy Charities, 2008; 2011; 2013 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Work Funded by McCarthy Charities (St. Jude, St. Augustine, Sacred Heart School), 2010; 2012-2013; 2015 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Yates Arts in Education Magnet School, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Zoller Elementary School (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Grant Funding, 1978-2016; 2; 6.0 cubic ft.
  Grant applications are large packets of records and require several forms of documentation from applicants to serve as evidence of an individual or institution's ability to legally and responsibly utilize the monies that could be awarded to them. The grant applications and supporting documents featured in the Grant Funding series are no different and as such feature the same type of documents throughout, regardless of the year. The Music Mobile was prompted to provide financial information that almost always included papers dated from 1979 and 1986. It was also required to provide promotional information, which almost always included newspaper clippings (or copies of newspaper clippings) from a range of dates, some further from the application year than others, as well as flyers and posters, which were considered undated by the processor because they do not have print dates associated with them. All of these factors extended the range of dates featured on the folder titles.
  Moreover, Pelham applied to and received several varieties of legislative grants with various (and sometimes similar sounding) names from several legislative officials. The archivist retained her naming conventions for these grants in the folder titles.
  Researchers will see personal and inter-office communication interleaved in this series. They take many forms, from familiar post-its to napkins and paper plates—all evidence of the grant funding process in its lengthy, chaotic glory.
  - Mohawk-Hudson Community Foundation Grants, 1978-1984; 1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1995 CDB6 Application-Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project, 1979; 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 97/98 Legislative Initiative Grant-McEneny, 1979; 1985; 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Legislative Local Initiative Grant for Daycare Training Project, 1979; 1985; 1998-2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 2007-2008 Legislative Initiative Grant (Tonko), 1979; 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1996 CDBG Application-Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project, 1979; 1986; 1988; 1994-1996; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1997 CDBG Application-Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project - RESTRICTED, 1979; 1986; 1990; 1994-1997; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1998 CDBG Application-Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project - RESTRICTED (1 of 2), 1979; 1986; 1990; 1994-1998; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1998 CDBG Application-Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project - RESTRICTED (2 of 2), 1979; 1986; 1990; 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1994 CDBG Final Report and 1995 CDBG Proposal, 1979; 1986; 1994-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 2002 CDBG Application-Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project, 1979; 1986; 1994-1995; 1997; 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1999 CDBG Application-Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project (North Albany, Arbor Hill, West Hill Neighborhoods), 1979; 1986; 1994-1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 2000 CDBG Application-Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project, 1979; 1986; 1994-2000; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 2001 CDBG Application-Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project, 1979; 1986; 1994-2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Music Mobile CBDG Van Grant 2010-2011 Year 36, 1979; 1986; 1995; 2002-2010; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Albany/Schenectady League of Arts 1998 Community Arts Connection, 1979; 1986; 1996-1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project 2005 CDBG Application, 1979; 1986; 1997; 2001-2005; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - CDBG Year 32 06-07, 1979; 1986; 1997; 2002-2006; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Music Mobile CDBG Application 07-08, 1979; 1986; 1997; 2002-2006; Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - CDBG 08-09, 1979; 1986; 1999; 2006-2008; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 2003 CDBG Application - Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project, 1979; 1986; 2001-2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 2004 CDBG Application - Music Mobile's "All Together Now!" Youth Project, 1979; 1986; 2001-2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Music Mobile, Inc CBDG 2010-2011 Year 36, 1979; 1986; 2002; 2008-2009; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Special State Grants With NYS Office of Parks, Recreation, and Historic Preservation (senator Bruno), 1979; 1986; 2003; 2006 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - CDBG Year 37 Application and Letters of Support, 1979; 1986; 2006-2011 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - CDBG Year 41 Application, 1979; 1986; 2006; 2014-2015; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Copy of Financial Statements, 1979; 2010-2012; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - CDBG Year 38 Application, 1979; 2011-2012; Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Mohawk-Hudson Community Foundation/Bank Contribution Clearing House, 1980; 1990-1996; Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Albany/Schenectady League of Arts Community, Arts Connection Grants and Non Profit Development Organization Research, 1982; 1985; 1993; 1997-1999; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bank Contributions Clearinghouse, 1985-1986; 1991-1992; 1994-1995; 1997; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1994 Decentralization Plan for the Capital Region, 1986; 1988; 1992-1994; Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 2004 Community Arts Connection Grant, 1986; 1996-1998; 2000-2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)